brother
형
Has it been a while since the two of us had a meal alone like this?
우리 둘이 이렇게 단둘이 식사를 한 건 오랜만이지?
I don't remember either
나도 기억이 안 나
do
도
My brother has become increasingly quiet since returning from the south.
형은 남쪽에서 돌아온 이후로 점점 과묵해졌습니다.
stay with me every day
매일 나와 함께 있어줘
All about those spices, workshop work
그 향신료에 관한 모든 것, 작업장 일
Nothing changes now that we are married.
이제 우리가 결혼했다고 해서 달라지는 건 없어요.
Brother, do you still miss the days when you ran a store in the south?
형님, 아직도 남쪽에서 가게를 운영하시던 시절이 그리워요 ?
Actually, I'm feeling better now
사실 지금은 좀 괜찮아요
Is your brother willing to go back south?
그 형은 남쪽으로 돌아갈 의향이 있습니까?
What does impersonation mean?
가장은 무엇을 의미합니까?
The Meng family monopolizes power in the southern stores.
맹씨 가문이 남부 상점의 권력을 독점하다
Now my ambitions are getting bigger and bigger
이제 야망은 점점 더 커져가
I need someone to check and balance.
확인하고 균형을 잡아줄 사람이 필요해요
There are so many great executives in the city.
도시에는 훌륭한 임원이 너무 많습니다.
Head of household can choose anyone else
가장은 다른 사람을 선택할 수 있습니다
Director Meng's Jurisdiction over Southern Stores
남부 상점에 대한 Meng 이사의 관할권
At that time, it was my brother who took the initiative to let you go.
그때 앞장서서 너를 내보내준 건 다 형이었어.
There's no one better suited than you to take it back
그것을 다시 가져가는 데 당신보다 더 적합한 사람은 없습니다
I had been away from the South for a number of years and things had changed.
나는 수년 동안 남부를 떠나 있었고 상황이 바뀌었습니다.
Please go back ‥
다시 돌아가세요 ‥
- I think it will be difficult for someone to convince me. -Brother, don't look down on yourself.
-누군가 나를 설득하기가 어려울 것 같습니다. -형님, 자신을 얕보지 마십시오.
Even though you've been back to Hwangcheong for so many years
비록 당신이 황청으로 오랜 세월 동안 돌아왔다고 해도
But in the end, it was you who single-handedly achieved the cause of South Korea, and everyone still remembers that.
하지만 결국 남한의 대의를 홀로 이룬 것은 바로 당신이었으며, 지금도 모두가 그것을 기억하고 있습니다.
You are still my father's only close disciple.
당신은 아직도 내 아버지의 유일한 가까운 제자입니다.
i know
알아요
This is because I took on the position of head of the household for the first time.
내가 처음으로 가장의 자리를 맡았기 때문이다.
All directors are watching with passionate eyes.
모든 감독님들이 뜨거운 눈빛으로 지켜보고 계십니다
Brother, do you want to reassure my mother?
형님, 우리 어머니를 안심시키고 싶나요?
To reassure me again
또 나를 안심시키기 위해서
So, I transferred all jurisdiction over Nanfang Store .
그래서 난팡상점에 대한 모든 관할권을 제가 이양했습니다 .
but now
그러나 지금
i need you
난 네가 필요해
say
말해
What do you want me to do?
내가 무엇을 하기를 바라나요?
I would like to take on the position of general manager of the southern branch.
남부점 총지배인 자리를 맡고 싶습니다.
please give it back
다시 돌려주세요
Because you are worried that the Meng family is monopolizing power,
맹씨 가문이 권력을 독점하고 있는 것을 걱정하고 계시기 때문에,
Are you not worried about me?
내 걱정은 안 되니?
If you wish, you can do so as soon as I assume the position of head of the household .
원하시면 이르면 제가 가장의 자리를 맡는 대로 하실 수 있습니다 .
After all, you have the power
결국, 당신은 힘이 있습니다
You have been kind-hearted since you were young.
당신은 어릴 때부터 마음씨가 착했어요.
But never give in to anyone
하지만 절대 누구에게도 굴복하지 마세요
It's rare to see you praise me like that.
당신이 나를 그렇게 칭찬하는 걸 보기가 드물어요
Is that senior willing to help me?
그 선배가 나를 도와줄 의향이 있나요?
When should we start?
언제 시작할까요?
I will make an announcement to all the bishops after the banquet this month .
이번 달 연회가 끝난 후 모든 감독님들 앞에서 발표하겠습니다.
brother
형
- Why is she here? -I came to see her mother.
- 그 여자가 왜 여기 있어요? - 어머니를 만나러 왔어요
I thought she had a grudge against the woman who made a mistake in the past.
그 여자는 예전에 실수한 여자한테 원한을 갖고 있는 줄 알았는데
will never come again
다시는 오지 않을 거야
It's my fault
내가 잘 못 했어
From this time on
이때부터
Thank you for your hard work, Grandma.
노고에 감사드립니다, 할머니.
It’s not difficult‥
어렵지 않다‥
Please go quickly
빨리 가세요
daughter
딸
your daughter has come to see you
당신의 딸이 당신을 만나러 왔습니다
My daughter is unfilial.
딸이 불효자다
make mom suffer
엄마를 고통스럽게 해라
But mom, don't worry
하지만 엄마, 걱정하지 마세요
diarrhea
설사
My brother is not here
형은 여기 없어
As long as my daughter is here
내 딸이 여기 있는 한
I will never let anyone make me angry.
나는 결코 누구도 나를 화나게 하도록 두지 않을 것이다.
daughter
딸
my daughter misses you
내 딸이 당신을 그리워해요
Qian Er
치엔얼
It's my mom's fault
엄마 탓이야
Mother still blamed Qian’er.
어머니는 여전히 Qian'er를 비난했습니다.
Mom made Qian'er sad
엄마가 Qian'er를 슬프게 만들었어
It's my mom's fault
엄마 탓이야
Good daughter, don’t blame your mother.
착한 딸아, 엄마를 원망하지 마라
I heard you and your mother reconciled?
당신과 어머니가 화해했다고 들었는데?
My father said that, but when did I fight with my mother?
아버지가 그러셨는데, 제가 언제 어머니와 싸웠나요?
what?
무엇?
yes, no problem
네, 문제 없어요
I wish I could have gotten closer to my mom earlier.
엄마랑 좀 더 일찍 친해질 수 있었으면 좋았을 텐데.
It's not too late now
이제 늦지 않았어
girl
소녀
Girl, I answered.
아가씨, 내가 대답했어
Time flies so fast
세월 참 빠르다
Qian Er
치엔얼
What happened today?
오늘 무슨 일이 있었나요?
Why do you seem hesitant to speak up?
왜 말하기를 주저하는 것 같나요?
A banquet will be held at Jungsiwon tomorrow, the 5th day of the Lunar New Year.
설날 5일인 내일 중시원에서 연회가 열립니다
I think it would be better for my mother not to go to the banquet.
내 생각에는 어머니가 연회에 가지 않는 것이 좋을 것 같다.
There are a lot of people in the servant's garden, and the mother's health is not good.
종의 정원에는 사람이 많고 어머니의 건강이 좋지 않습니다.
That too
그것도 그렇죠
So what can you see at the banquet in Zhongshi Garden?
그렇다면 중시원(Zhongshi Garden)의 연회에서는 무엇을 볼 수 있을까요?
Over the past half month, I have pretty much taken over every task at hand.
지난 반달 동안 나는 당면한 모든 업무를 거의 인계했습니다.
Wait until the banquet is over
연회가 끝날 때까지 기다리세요
I should be able to resign from my position as capital manager.
나는 자본관리자로서의 직위를 사임할 수 있어야 합니다.
Then it will be as you said...
그럼 당신이 말한 대로 되겠죠…
How about going to the small town of Jiangnan to recuperate?
강남(Jiangnan)의 작은 마을로 가서 요양을 하는 것은 어떨까요?
Like this
이런 식으로
charming
매우 좋은
correct
옳은
Did your father have a personal relationship with the young head of the Wu family?
당신의 아버지는 우 가문의 젊은 당주와 개인적인 관계를 갖고 있었습니까?
right
오른쪽
At first, Mu Yunping could not tell the difference between the inferior agarwood.
무운핑은 처음에는 열등한 침향의 차이를 구별할 수 없었습니다.
I got a fragrant recipe from him
그에게서 향기로운 요리법을 얻었습니다
This is because they accepted the Ge family that they once ran away from.
한때 도망쳤던 게씨 가문을 받아들였기 때문이다.
How can that be?
어떻게 그럴 수 있습니까?
How is that impossible?
어떻게 불가능합니까?
But in the past...
하지만 과거에는 ......
In the past, there was obviously nothing like Wu Shuomo taking over the Ge family.
과거에는 Wu Shuomo가 Ge 가족을 인수하는 것과 같은 것이 분명히 없었습니다 .
He eventually helped Mu Yao.
그는 결국 Mu Yao를 도왔습니다.
Fahrenheit becomes the driving force behind destruction
화씨파멸의 원동력이 되다
How is it possible to cooperate with the Father now?
지금 아버지와 협력하는 것이 어떻게 가능합니까?
What's wrong?
무엇이 잘못되었나요?
What's the problem?
무슨 문제 있어?
that‥
그‥
He is from the Wu family, why would he interfere in the affairs of the Zhong family?
그는 우 가문 출신인데 왜 종 가문의 일에 간섭하겠습니까?
That's because he comes from the Wu family.
바로 그가 우 가문 출신이기 때문이다.
Don't worry if you use it
사용하시면 걱정하지 마세요
Is she gentle by nature?
그녀는 본질적으로 온화합니까?
Is she timid?
그녀는 소심한가요?
When did you suffer from eye disease?
언제 안질환을 앓으셨나요?
Of course I know my daughter well.
물론 나는 내 딸을 잘 알고 있다.
You guys truly have a deep love as father and daughter.
너희들은 정말 아버지와 딸로서 깊은 사랑을 갖고 있다.
If you want to express your feelings
마음을 표현하고 싶다면
not a bad idea
나쁜 생각은 아니야
you say
당신은 말한다
Now you're here pretending to be calm
지금 넌 여기서 침착한 척하고 있어
How dare you threaten me?
어떻게 감히 나를 위협합니까?
Aren’t you really afraid that I might cooperate with you?
내가 당신에게 협조할까봐 정말 두렵지 않습니까?
Do you want to make it public?
공개로 설정하시겠습니까?
Cooperation between me and the young teacher
나와 젊은 스승의 협력
I am afraid that the young master might not want others to know about this. Yes?
젊은 스승님은 다른 사람들이 이 사실을 알기를 바라지 않을까 걱정됩니다. 그렇죠?
In order to steal the fragrant recipe, the Wu family
향기로운 제조법을 훔치기 위해 우씨 일가는
At the risk of being criticized and insulted by others, the wanted Ge family must be kept secret.
다른 사람들의 비난과 모욕을 당할 위험을 무릅쓰고 수배된 Ge 가족을 비밀리에 숨겨야 합니다.
He then began secretly making counterfeit incense.
그런 다음 그는 비밀리에 가짜 향약을 만들기 시작했습니다.
this problem
이 문제
I wonder if the old head of the Wu family knows.
우 가문의 옛 당주가 알고 있는지 궁금합니다.
Or is this a selfish act of a young head of a family?
아니면 젊은 가장의 이기적인 행동 인가요 ?
I just gave you a perfume recipe.
방금 향수 레시피를 알려드렸는데요
Convenient for framing colleagues.
동료를 모함하는 데 편리합니다.
Why did you say it so nicely in the first place?
애초에 왜 그렇게 좋게 말했지?
Are you now crossing the river, burning the bridge, turning your back and denying others?
지금 당신은 강을 건너고 다리를 불태우고 등을 돌리고 다른 사람을 부인하고 있습니까?
Of course I know that young master.
물론 나는 그 젊은 스승을 알고 있다.
What is the thinking behind this move?
이 움직임 뒤에는 어떤 생각이 있습니까?
But what about the fight within the Zhong family now?
하지만 지금 종씨 가문 내부의 싸움은 어떻습니까?
Unfortunately, I have nothing to do with that young master.
유감스럽게도 그 젊은 스승과는 아무 관련이 없습니다.
Young Patriarch, unfortunately I cannot say that you are at a disadvantage.
젊은 총대주교님, 불행하게도 당신이 불리하다고 말할 수는 없습니다.
Moreover, the young head of the household is now very passionate about the work of the head family.
게다가 젊은 가장은 이제 종가의 일에 너무나 열정적입니다.
Have you already decided not to do business with that company anymore ?
더 이상 그 회사와 거래하지 않기로 이미 결정하셨나요 ?
you two, father and daughter
너희 둘, 아버지와 딸
It is actually carved from the same mold.
그것은 실제로 같은 틀에서 조각된 것입니다.
I love using this to kill a thousand enemies.
나는 이것을 사용하여 천 명의 적을 죽이는 것을 좋아합니다.
Threatening others through self-destruction
자기 파괴를 통해 다른 사람을 위협하는 행위
so
그래서
After wanting to invite the young master
젊은 스승님을 초대하고 싶은 후
Be careful what you say and do
말과 행동을 조심하라
When news leaks out
소식이 새어나오면
I will lose myself a thousand dollars
나는 나 자신에게 천 달러를 잃을 것이다
It will never grant you peace
그것은 결코 당신에게 평화를 허락하지 않을 것입니다
This problem is actually a bit dangerous.
이 문제는 사실 좀 위험해요
It was something he and I did privately, and no third party knew about it.
그 일은 그와 내가 개인적으로 한 일이었고, 제3자는 이 사실을 알지 못했습니다.
So I didn't mention this to you before.
그래서 나는 이전에 이것을 당신에게 언급하지 않았습니다.
No matter how much I check
아무리 확인해도
That person will not be revealed
그 사람은 밝혀지지 않을 거야
Qian Er
치엔얼
don't worry
걱정 하지마
He knows what he can and cannot say
그는 말할 수 있는 것과 말할 수 없는 것을 알고 있다
No one will know about it unless I mention it .
내가 언급하지 않는 한 아무도 그것에 대해 알 수 없습니다.
It's true that no one knows
아무도 알아주지 않는 것이 사실이다
Otherwise
그렇지 않으면
You wouldn't know it now
지금은 몰랐을 텐데
I didn't hide it from you on purpose.
일부러 너에게 숨긴 건 아니야
good
좋은
If you want to know anything now, just ask me.
지금 무엇이든 알고 싶다면 나에게 물어보세요.
Father, can you tell me the specific process of dealing with the Mu family?
아버지는 무 가족을 대하는 구체적인 과정을 나에게 말해 주실 수 있습니까?
good
좋은
me too......
나도......
understood
이해했다
It's not too early
너무 이르진 않아
I'm going to Zhongshi Garden tomorrow.
내일 중시 정원에 갈 거예요
Dad, please rest early.
아버지, 일찍 쉬세요
Qian Er
치엔얼
what's the problem?
뭐가 문제 야?
this bitch
이 년
I have always sought power and wealth.
나는 항상 권력과 부를 추구해왔습니다.
I have neglected you and your brother a lot.
나는 당신과 당신의 형제를 많이 무시했습니다.
you are wise
당신은 현명합니다
I feel sorry for my brother
형이 불쌍하다
I didn't teach him well.
내가 그 사람을 잘 가르치지 않았어.
Why did my father suddenly say this?
아버지는 왜 갑자기 이런 말씀을 하신 걸까요?
after getting married
결혼한 후에
He speaks and acts differently than usual, and is very distant from us.
평소와는 말투나 행동이 다르고, 우리와도 많이 멀어져 있습니다.
i see all this
나는 이것을 모두 본다
I asked, but they didn't tell me.
물어봤는데 안 알려주시더라구요
i am always thinking
나는 항상 생각하고 있다
what's the matter?
왜 그래?
How can that be? Your father is thinking too much.
어떻게 그럴 수가 있지? 아버지가 너무 생각하고 계시는구나.
It wasn't until your brother passed away that I started to understand
네 형이 세상을 떠나고 나서야 난 이해하기 시작했어
I don't deserve to be a father.
나는 아버지가 될 자격이 없어요.
Absolutely from your point of view
절대 네 입장에서는
So, if something happens, the daughter cannot speak honestly to her father.
그래서 딸은 무슨 일이 생기면 아버지에게 솔직하게 말을 하지 못한다 .
now
지금
as long as you are good
당신이 좋은 한
All your worries are over
걱정은 다 끝났어
Father, don't say that. You have done well enough.
아버지, 그런 말씀하지 마세요. 당신은 할 만큼 잘하셨습니다.
It's all me...
다 나야 ‥
I had a dream on my wedding night
결혼식 날 밤에 꿈을 꾸었어요
I dreamed that everyone in the Hua family died violently.
Hua 가족이 모두 폭력적으로 죽는 꿈을 꾸었습니다
That dream is so real
그 꿈은 너무 현실적이야
i am thinking
나는 생각 중입니다
Is this a warning from God?
이것이 하나님의 경고인가?
So since then
그래서 그 이후로
I will change my past behavior
나는 과거의 행동을 바꿀 것이다
But it's okay now I'm here
하지만 괜찮아 이제 난 여기 있어
I will definitely protect my father
나는 반드시 아버지를 지켜낼 것이다
and Huajia Zhouquan.
그리고 화지아 저우취안(Huajia Zhouquan)
good daughter
좋은 딸
go and rest
가서 쉬어라
oh my god
맙소사
you are so cruel
당신은 너무 잔인 해요
do it again
다시 할
Why did you dig such a big hole for me?
왜 나를 위해 그렇게 큰 구멍을 파셨나요?
girl
소녀
Please help me call Hua Rongzhou
Hua Rongzhou에 전화할 수 있게 도와주세요
yes
예
My father will resign in a few days.
아버지가 며칠 있으면 사임하실 거야
I just discussed it with him.
방금 그 사람이랑 의논했어
I plan to settle in Gangnam.
나는 강남에 정착할 계획이다.
So go tomorrow and help me with what you can.
그러니까 내일 가서 내가 할 수 있는 일 좀 도와줘
Let's go find a nice house over there so we can settle down in the future.
앞으로 우리가 정착할 수 있도록 저기 좋은 집을 구하러 가자 .
Why should I go early?
왜 일찍 가야 하나요?
It's like they're trying to chase me away
마치 나를 쫓아내려는 것 같아
I think it would be better to prepare early
일찍 준비하는 것이 좋을 것 같아요
This way, you won’t have to rush when moving.
이렇게 하면 이사할 때 서두르지 않아도 됩니다.
So go ahead and grab a seat.
그러니 먼저 가서 자리를 잡으세요.
Then wait until we leave.
그럼 우리가 떠날 때까지 기다리세요
in my yard
내 마당에서
The only two people left are you and Qian Zhi.
남은 사람은 당신과 Qian Zhi, 두 사람뿐입니다.
Qian Zhi will stay in Huangcheng when the time comes
Qian Zhi는 때가 되면 황청에 머무를 것입니다
So the only person I can use and trust is you.
그러니까 내가 쓸 수 있고 믿을 수 있는 사람은 너뿐이야.
But I still get the feeling that the girl is thinking of ways to kick me out.
하지만 나는 여전히 그 소녀가 나를 쫓아낼 방법을 생각하고 있다는 느낌이 듭니다.
You will only be gone for half a month at most.
당신은 기껏해야 반달 동안만 떠나있을 것입니다.
Will Huaihai and I be able to escape from the imperial city in such a short period of time ?
이렇게 짧은 시간 안에 화자이와 나는 황성에서 도망칠 수 있을까요?
I think it would be nice to go together when the time comes.
시간되면 같이 가면 좋을 것 같아요
I'm not really worried about leaving the girl here alone.
나는 그 소녀를 여기에 혼자 남겨 두는 것에 대해 정말로 걱정하지 않습니다.
There are so many people guarding such a large yard.
이렇게 넓은 마당을 지키는 사람들이 너무 많아요
What are you worried about?
당신은 무엇을 걱정합니까?
I asked him to do something, but he kept getting pushed back and forth.
뭐 좀 해달라고 했는데 계속 밀리고 왔다 갔다 하더군요.
If you don't want to do it, just say so.
하기 싫으면 그냥 그렇다고 말하세요.
It's not that I don't want to do it.
하기 싫다는 건 아니야
Then I'll leave tomorrow.
그럼 내일 이만 갈게요
Okay, then I'll wait to hear from you.
알았어, 그럼 네 소식을 기다릴게.
Choose a few more places to live and then let your father decide.
살 곳을 몇 군데 더 선택 하고 그 다음에는 아버지가 결정하게 하세요.
Don't choose a house that is too rich.
집은 너무 부유한 곳을 선택하지 마세요.
But don't go too far.
하지만 너무 멀리 있지는 마세요.
After all, this is where we will live in the future.
결국, 이곳은 우리가 미래에 살 곳입니다.
You better pay more attention
좀 더 주의를 기울이는 게 좋을 거야
what the girl said
그 소녀가 말한 것
Of course there's nothing I can do
물론 내가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없어
It's just hope
그냥 희망이야
You can keep your promises, but don't lie.
약속은 지킬 수도 있어요, 거짓말은 하지 마세요
Didn't I say I never lie? What other concerns do you have?
나는 절대 거짓말을 하지 않는다고 하지 않았나요? 또 어떤 걱정이 있나요?
Then I'll go tomorrow
그럼 내일 갈게요
strangeness
기묘
Obviously there is no perfume in this house.
분명히 이 집에는 향수가 하나도 없거든요.
Why does it always smell familiar?
왜 항상 익숙한 향기가 나는 걸까요?
Do you smell it?
냄새가 나나요?
have
가지다
Does it really smell?
정말 냄새가 나나요?
It's the scent on the girl's body.
소녀의 몸에 있는 향이에요
But I don't use any scent at all
하지만 난 향을 전혀 사용하지 않아
But to that woman
하지만 그 여자한테는
There is always a scent
언제나 향기가 있어요
-How about this? -I can't know for sure either.
-어떤가요? -나도 확실히 알 수는 없다.
but very special
하지만 아주 특별한
From the first time I met a woman
여자를 처음 만났을 때부터
The scent of your body has never changed
네 몸의 향기는 한 번도 변하지 않았어
Forget it, you're leaving tomorrow
잊어버려, 넌 내일 떠날 거야
Go down and rest early.
내려가서 일찍 쉬세요.
good
좋은
Go to Gangnam and select your home location
강남으로 가서 집 위치를 선택하세요
Again and again
이번에도 몇 번이고
It will likely take at least 15 days
최소 보름은 걸릴 듯
What did she just say?
방금 그 여자가 뭐라고 말했어요?
naught
아무것도 아님
Do you smell me?
나에게서 냄새가 나나요?
no
아니요
The girl didn't use any scents during this period, so there was no smell.
소녀는 이 기간 동안 향을 전혀 사용하지 않았기 때문에 냄새도 나지 않았습니다.
I'm with my father today
오늘은 아버지와 함께 있어요
You don't have to come with me to the Garden of Bells.
종의 정원에 나와 함께 갈 필요는 없습니다.
Mom's health has improved these days.
요즘 엄마의 건강이 좋아졌어요
look at her for me
나를 위해 그녀를 봐
Is everything sorted out?
다 정리됐나요?
girl
소녀
You must remember and come to me quickly
꼭 기억하고 빨리 나를 찾아와야 해
Otherwise I'll come back for you
그렇지 않으면 내가 다시 당신을 찾으러 올게요
good
좋은
safe travel
안전한 여행
Okay, let me all toast.
자, 내가 모두 건배하자
polite‥
예의 바른‥
Siwoo‥
시우‥
thank you, mother
고마워요, 어머니
Sister Hua was so worried that she called me.
화 자매님이 너무 걱정스러워서 저를 불렀어요
What is it for?
그것은 무엇을 위한 것입니까?
My sister seems so cold and indifferent
내 여동생은 너무 차갑고 무심해 보여
You haven't paid much attention to me these days either.
요즘 너도 나한테 별로 관심을 안 줬잖아.
Did something happen?
무슨 일이라도 있었나요?
Stop playing this sisterly love game.
이 자매 사랑 게임을 중단하세요.
It's disgusting
역겹다
What happened to my sister today?
오늘 내 여동생에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
The owner is allergic to lychee nectar.
주인은 리치 넥타에 알레르기가 있습니다.
Have you forgotten Teacher Meng?
멩 선생님은 잊어버리셨나요?
And this problem?
그리고 이 문제는요?
I just thought the landlord liked sweet things.
집주인이 단맛을 좋아하는 줄만 알았지
I think he likes this lychee juice too.
그 사람도 이 리치 과즙을 좋아하는 것 같아요.
Is that why you became so distant?
언니가 이렇게 멀어진 건 그것 때문인가요?
- I really don't know. - Aren't you tired of acting like this every day?
- 정말 모르겠어요. - 매일매일 이렇게 행동하는 게 지겹지 않나요?
Who did my sister listen to? The owner of the house does not eat honey
내 여동생은 누구의 말을 들었나요? 집주인은 꿀을 먹지 않는다
He spoke to me privately.
그는 나에게 개인적으로 말했다.
Such a clumsy trick
이런 서투른 트릭
It's quite refreshing to use.
사용해보면 꽤 상쾌합니다.
do you think
당신은 생각합니까
I won't ask Zhong Xiwu personally
나는 Zhong Xiwu에게 개인적으로 묻지 않을 것입니다
I don't think anyone still knows what you said to me that day .
그날 당신이 나에게 무슨 말을 했는지는 아직도 아무도 모르는 것 같아요.
Can you push it out cleanly?
깔끔하게 밀어낼 수 있나요?
My sister did something really wrong to me.
내 여동생이 나에게 정말 큰 잘못을 저질렀어요.
If you keep acting like this
계속 이런 식으로 행동하면
Then there is nothing to talk about today.
그럼 오늘은 할 얘기가 없잖아
What should we talk about?
무엇에 대해 이야기할까요?
say‥
말하다‥
Why do you want to kill me?
왜 나를 죽이고 싶나요?
-You... -Because I asked.
-당신은‥ -내가 물었으니까
That means I'm sure you don't need to act any further
그것은 내가 확신 하고 당신이 더 이상 행동할 필요가 없다는 것을 의미합니다
Rely on your cautious nature
조심성 있는 성격에 의지하세요
I guess they brought someone here now.
지금 누군가를 여기로 데려왔나 봐요
I am sure you have checked these 4 weeks.
나는 당신이 이 4주를 확인했다고 확신합니다.
There's no one here but you and me
여기엔 너와 나 외에는 아무도 없어
So I am not deceiving you when I say this.
그러므로 내가 이렇게 말하는 것은 당신을 속이는 것이 아닙니다.
Why do you think so?
왜 그렇게 생각하시나요?
you told me directly
당신은 나에게 직접 말했다
I mentioned it by chance some time ago.
예전에 우연히 언급했는데
The person who assassinated me at the Chuseok luncheon was targeting me.
추석 오찬에서 나를 암살한 사람이 나를 노리고 있었다.
You weren't surprised to hear this at all
넌 이 말을 듣고 전혀 놀라지 않았어
Turns out, that's when you started doubting me
알고보니 그때부터 넌 나를 의심하기 시작했지
Miss Meng always treated me differently from ordinary people.
Miss Meng은 항상 나를 평범한 사람들과 다르게 대했습니다.
I ask myself, I have no merit.
나는 공로가 없다고 스스로에게 묻습니다.
So doubt is inevitable.
그러니 의심은 피할 수 없다.
Originally it was just a normal question.
원래는 그냥 평범한 질문이었는데
There was an unexpected benefit
뜻밖에도 뜻밖의 이득이 있었다
Because you told me to come alone
나한테 혼자 오라고 했기 때문에
It's just empty talk, right?
그냥 공허한 얘기겠죠?
i still can't understand it
나는 아직도 그것을 이해할 수 없다
Why are you committing murder against me ?
당신이 나에게 살인을 저지르는 이유는 무엇입니까 ?
I blame you for overestimating your abilities.
당신의 능력을 과대평가한 당신을 비난합니다.
You used a plan to catch Zong Ye-ran , so why bother provoking the landlord?
당신이 종예란을 잡기 위해 계략을 썼는데 , 왜 굳이 집주인을 자극합니까?
Working 24 hours a day and being greedy like this
24시간 일하고 이렇게 욕심을 부려
It's so disgusting I can't stand it
너무 역겨워서 참을 수 없어
Look at the people in the bell garden Who likes you?
종 정원에 있는 사람들을 보세요 누가 당신을 좋아하나요?
When did I provoke Jong Hee-woo?
내가 언제 종희우를 자극했는가?
Do you think I'm stupid?
내가 바보라고 생각하세요?
Since you got married, you have been frequenting the servant’s garden.
당신은 결혼한 이후로 종의 정원에 자주 드나들었습니다.
Only then did the landlord gradually start to look at you differently.
그제서야 집주인은 점차 당신을 다르게 바라보게 되었습니다.
The head of the household always values ​​friendship among family members.
가장은 항상 가족 간의 우정을 소중히 여깁니다.
If you didn't provoke me on purpose
일부러 나를 자극하지 않았다면
How could he think differently about you?
그 사람이 어떻게 당신에 대해 다른 생각을 할 수 있겠어요?
You also said it was Zhongxi Wusheng's idea.
당신도 Zhongxi Wusheng의 생각이라고 말했어요
So why was it me who was killed in the end?
그렇다면 결국 살해당한 것은 왜 나였는가?
Why can only soft persimmons be pinched?
왜, 부드러운 감만 꼬집을 수 있습니까?
If you are innocent, of course I won't interfere.
당신이 결백하다면 나는 당연히 간섭하지 않을 것입니다
It's strange that she's an abandoned woman.
버림받은 여자라니 이상해
Still dreaming about what you don't deserve
아직도 당신이 받을 자격이 없는 일에 대한 꿈을 꾸고 있습니다
How can I watch you destroy Zhongshiyuan’s inner house?
당신이 Zhongshiyuan의 내부 집을 파괴하는 것을 내가 어떻게 지켜볼 수 있습니까 ?
Why are you smiling?
왜 웃고 있어?
I laugh at your duplicity.
나는 너의 이중성을 비웃는다
You're clearly afraid that I'm going to take your place
내가 네 자리를 빼앗아갈까 봐 분명히 두려워하고 있지
But he can still speak righteously
하지만 그는 여전히 의롭게 말할 수 있다
It’s for Jong Hee-woo’s inner self.
종희우의 내면을 위해서다
the big princess is still alive
큰 공주는 아직 살아있다
You're just a temporary resident in a big house.
넌 그냥 큰 집에 임시로 사는 사람일 뿐이야
it's up to you
그것은 당신에게 달렸습니다
Is it worth maintaining the stability of the species' garden house?
종의 정원 가옥의 안정성을 유지할 가치가 있습니까?
You are only relying on yourself now . You are the daughter of the head family.
당신은 지금 자신에게만 의지하고 있습니다 .당신은 종가의 딸입니다.
What right does an abandoned woman have to accuse me?
버림받은 여자가 무슨 권리로 나를 고발해야 합니까?
So what happens if I stay temporarily?
그럼 임시로 머무르면 어떻게 되나요?
at least i am innocent
적어도 나는 결백하다
She is also the future wife of the Zong family, designated by the eldest daughter.
그녀는 또한 장녀가 지정한 종 가문의 미래 부인이기도 합니다.
you are afraid of me
당신은 나를 두려워합니다
Not just because I want to
단지 내가 원해서가 아니라
Would I be able to easily trample you under foot?
내가 쉽게 당신을 발로 짓밟을 수 있을까요?
The position of the mistress of the head family
종가의 여주인의 지위
i tell you
나는 당신에게 말한다
This time, I will never be able to sit in that seat again.
이번에는 다시는 그 자리에 앉을 수 없을 것이다.
you should thank me
나한테 고마워해야 해
thank you for letting me go
널 보내줘서 고마워
I do not want the position of mistress of the head family at all.
나는 종가의 여주인의 지위를 전혀 원하지 않습니다.
But you did this to me
그런데 당신이 나한테 이런 짓을 한 거예요
I almost surprised you
난 당신을 거의 놀라게 했어요
It became reality
현실이 되었다
Bitch, you...
이년아, 너......
You can't resist telling the truth, can you?
진실을 말하는 걸 참을 수가 없잖아요, 그렇죠?
Your pampered life has really ruined you.
당신의 응석받이 생활이 당신을 정말로 망쳤습니다.
The speed at which it hits people is too slow.
사람을 때리는 속도가 너무 느려요
Are you still waiting for others to show you face?
당신은 아직도 다른 사람들이 당신에게 얼굴을 내밀기를 기다리고 있습니까?
-Let go... -How dare you scream?
-놔 ‥ - 감히 소리 지르는구나
Watch your face
얼굴 조심해
-You dare -Why don't I dare?
-당신은 감히 -나는 왜 감히하지 않습니까?
Do you think I'm being too kind?
내가 너무 친절하다고 생각하시나요?
I say, listen to me.
내가 말하노니 내 말을 들어라
This is because he despises the position of the mistress of the head family.
종가의 여주인의 지위를 경멸하기 때문이다
It's not that I'm afraid of you.
내가 당신을 두려워하는 것은 아닙니다.
a place you cherish
당신이 소중히 여기는 곳
I can't even look at you
쳐다보지도 못해요
Are you sane?
제정신이에요?
Aren't you afraid that one day I will ask the head of the household to fire Hwadugwan?
언젠가 내가 가장에게 화두관을 해고하라고 요구할까봐 두렵지 않습니까?
-Would you like to be kicked out of Hwangcheong? -I don't think I'll ever have an opportunity like this again.
-황청에서 쫓아내시겠습니까? -이런 기회는 다시는 없을 것 같아요.
How dare you do this to me today?
오늘 감히 나에게 이런 짓을 하다니
Even the head of the household will not be able to protect you for some time.
심지어 가장도 한동안은 당신을 보호할 수 없을 것입니다.
Believe it or not, whatever you do today
믿거나 말거나 오늘은 뭘 하든
Will Zhong Xiwu suppress it and not pursue it?
Zhong Xiwu는 그것을 진압하고 추구하지 않을 것입니까?
Don't think your brother stopped the sword for you
네 놈의 형이 널 위해 칼을 막았다고 생각하지 마
It'll be okay
괜찮아 질거야
One day, no one in your Chinese family will be doing well.
어느 날, 당신의 중국인 가족 중 누구도 잘 살지 못할 것입니다.
you‥
너‥
blood‥
피‥
If it weren't for Jong Hee-woo's taboo
종희우의 금기가 아니었다면
How could I let you go so easily?
어떻게 그렇게 쉽게 널 보낼 수 있었을까?
A scar changed my brother's life
흉터가 내 형제의 삶을 바꾸었다
You took advantage of this.
당신은 이것을 이용했습니다.
Let's toast again
다시 건배하자
Mr. Jang, please come
장 선생님 오세요
Master, please tell the head of the family...
스승님, 가장에게 말씀해 주십시오‥
House owner
집주인
eat this
이거 먹어
This bacterium is rare
이 박테리아는 드물다
you try it
당신은 그것을 시도
If you think the food at the banquet is not delicious
잔치 음식이 맛없다고 생각된다면
Come back, dad will take you to eat something delicious.
돌아와요 아빠가 맛있는거 먹으러 데리러 갈게요
I am afraid that I will never have this opportunity.
이런 기회가 없을까 두렵습니다.
father
아버지
Whatever I do, just wait.
내가 뭘 하든 기다려줘
Everyone wants to protect our Hua family.
다들 우리 Hua 가족을 보호하고 싶어해
shallow girl
얕은 소녀
What are you going to do?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
I have something to report back to the head of the family, the eldest princess.
당주인 큰공주님께 돌아가서 보고할 것이 있습니다
what's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
confess
복죄하다
What crime?
무슨 범죄요?
Mu Yunping self-harm incident a year ago
1년 전 무윤핑 자해 사건
In fact, this piece was created by the Hua family.
사실 이 작품은 Hua 가족이 만든 것입니다.
Akian
아 키안
Confession letter from Ms. Qian, the toothless person involved in the incident
사건에 연루된 이가 빠진 사람 치안 여사의 고백편지
And the contract between them and the Fahrenheit family
그리고 그들과 화씨 가문의 계약
There are also photos and physical evidence of the people involved.
관련된 사람들의 사진과 물리적 증거도 있습니다.
all in my hands
모두 내 손에
proposal
제시
How is it going?
어떻게 되어가나요?
Madam Zhongzhai Mu, do you know about this?
Zhongzhai Mu 부인, 이것에 대해 알고 계십니까?
Hoegaju
회가주
I am a woman and I know nothing about economics and trade.
저는 여성이고 경제와 무역에 대해 아무것도 모릅니다.
It's just that my father left the city a long time ago due to the landlord's gift.
단지 아버지가 집주인의 선물로 인해 오래 전에 도시를 떠났을 뿐입니다.
Things from the past have long since been resolved.
과거의 일은 이미 해결된 지 오래다
Hwatu Hall
화투관
What do you think about Mu Yunping being framed?
무윤핑이 액자에 담긴 것에 대해 어떻게 생각하시나요?
Do you have any explanation?
설명할 게 있나요?
I plead guilty.
나는 유죄를 인정한다
Then drop off Hua Wenang.
그런 다음 Hua Wenang을 내려주세요.
We plan to verify these matters one by one in the future.
이 사항은 앞으로 하나씩 검증해 나갈 예정이다.
Huaqian
화첸
I know you have always been wise. Of course, I read that correctly.
나는 당신이 항상 현명했다는 것을 알고 있습니다. 물론, 나는 그것을 올바르게 읽었습니다.
The murder of your relatives is indeed an example to women.
당신의 친척 살해는 실제로 여성의 모범입니다.
I won't take my anger out on you
나는 당신에게 분노를 표출하지 않을 것입니다
-Garden of Bells‥ -Si Woo
-종의 정원 ‥ -시 우
Teacher, I have something else to tell you.
선생님, 또 드릴 말씀이 있어요
My father and the Mu family are both in charge of the Zong family.
나의 아버지와 무 가문은 모두 종 가문을 맡고 있습니다.
We have been working together for a long time and have nothing but sympathy and sympathy for each other.
우리는 오랫동안 함께 일해왔고 서로에 대한 공감과 공감 외에는 아무것도 없습니다.
He had no idea about the matter from beginning to end.
그 사람은 처음부터 끝까지 그 문제에 대해 전혀 몰랐어요
Actually I'm tired
사실은 피곤해요
This all happened because of my jealousy
이게 다 내 질투 때문에 일어난 일이야
In the past, I was happy for my uncle.
예전에는 삼촌한테 반가웠는데
They are narrow-minded and cannot tolerate others.
마음이 좁고 타인을 참지 못한다.
Fear Mu Yao with the heart of a villain
악당의 마음으로 무야오를 두려워하다
He did not hesitate to use this vicious tactic to eradicate the Mu family.
그는 무(Mu) 가문을 근절하기 위해 이 악랄한 책략을 서슴지 않고 사용했습니다.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
everything I said is true
내가 말한 모든 것은 사실이다
I was the one who secretly bribed the scent medicine workshop.
향기약 공방에 몰래 뇌물을 준 사람은 바로 나였다.
The original agarwood was replaced with inferior agarwood.
원래 침향을 열등한 침향으로 교체했습니다.
And through Ya Ren's hand, I was introduced to Mu Yao.
그리고 Ya Ren의 손을 통해 Mu Yao를 소개받았습니다.
Send furniture containing agarwood to Mujia.
침향이 포함된 가구를 무지아에게 보내기
Uncle and Mu Yao also know this.
삼촌과 무야오도 이 사실을 알고 있다.
They are generous and let bygones be bygones.
그들은 관대하며 지나간 일을 지나간 일로 여기고 있습니다.
And I have evidence of past crimes.
그리고 나는 과거 범죄에 대한 증거를 갖고 있습니다.
I'm really anxious
정말 불안하다
You can't avoid inner criticism
내면의 비난을 피할 수 없다
So I came today to apologize.
그래서 오늘 사과하러 왔어요
Because you proactively pleaded guilty.
당신이 주도적으로 유죄를 인정했기 때문에
Deposit first
먼저 입금하세요
Set a retrial date
재심 날짜를 정하세요
Could it be that the head of the family wants to interrogate the Hua family in court?
가장이 법정에서 화씨 가문을 심문하고 싶어하는 것은 아닐까?
My father walked upright and upright his whole life.
아버지는 평생 꼿꼿하고 꼿꼿하게 걸어오셨습니다.
But they always feel burdened by a pair of unsatisfied children.
그러나 그들은 항상 만족스럽지 못한 한 쌍의 아이들로 인해 부담을 느낍니다.
Hope, the head of the household and eldest daughter
가장, 장녀인 희망
Today, I took the initiative to plead guilty, so please do not implicate my father.
오늘은 제가 주도적으로 유죄를 인정했으니 아버지를 연루시키지 말아주세요.
I am prepared to endure all punishment without any resentment.
어떠한 원망도 없이 모든 처벌을 감수할 각오가 되어있습니다
stupid boy
바보 같은 소년
father's mistake
아버지의 실수
Why would you allow your daughter to suffer on your behalf?
어찌 당신을 대신해 딸이 고통받게 할 이유가 있겠습니까 ?
House owner
집주인
big princess
큰 공주
Mu Yunping, former head of the Zhong family
무윈핑(Mu Yunping) 전 종씨 가문의 당주
After being transferred from the north to the imperial castle to serve
북쪽에서 황성으로 옮겨져 복무하게 된 후
i am afraid
나는 두려워
I am afraid that my position as governor is threatened.
주지사로서의 내 지위가 위협받을까 두렵습니다.
Moreover, he and I also have different opinions on store management.
게다가 그와 나는 매장 운영에 있어서도 의견이 다르다.
constant language disputes
끊임없는 언어 분쟁
And the workshop I work under is increasingly in conflict with me.
그리고 그 밑에서 일하는 워크숍은 나와 점점 더 갈등을 빚고 있습니다.
Resentment accumulated over a long period of time
오랜 시간 쌓여온 원한
Before I know it, I hate myself and can’t let go.
나도 모르게 내가 미워지고 놓지 못해요
later
나중에
When I found out that my daughter was friends with Mu Yunping's daughter.
내 딸이 무윤핑 딸과 친구라는 사실을 알았을 때
It started there
거기서 시작된 거야
After that, I also found someone who exposed the fake Chenxiang Pill.
그 후 가짜 Chenxiang Pill을 폭로하는 사람도 찾았습니다.
Let regular customers buy it.
일반 고객이 구매하도록 하세요.
Take Mu Yunping to court
무윤핑(Mu Yunping)을 법정에 데려가세요
Father, you…
아버지, 당신은…
House owner
집주인
I have been responsible for everyone for decades.
나는 수십 년 동안 모두를 책임져 왔습니다.
In the end, he became greedy for profit.
결국 그는 이익에 욕심을 냈다.
Regardless of right or wrong, I just want to eradicate dissidents.
옳고 그름을 떠나 반체제 인사를 척결하고 싶을 뿐
ignoring justice
정의를 무시하고
But when I was young
하지만 어렸을 때
know your ethics
윤리를 알라
Qian'er also tried to persuade her with words several times.
Qian'er도 여러 번 말로 그녀를 설득하려고했습니다.
But I'm still stubborn
하지만 난 아직도 고집이 세다
she has a kind heart
그녀는 마음이 친절해요
I just took the initiative to plead guilty.
나는 방금 유죄를 인정하기 위해 주도권을 잡았습니다.
Filial piety simply involves taking on the responsibility of one's father.
단지 아버지의 책임을 지고 가는 것이 효도입니다.
- No, it's not. - Managers
- 아니요, 그렇지 않습니다. - 매니저들
Everyone knows about the argument between Mu Yunping and me.
무윤핑과 저 사이의 논쟁에 대해서는 모두가 알고 있습니다.
Today, I will explain everything clearly and ask for a lesson from even the head of the family.
오늘은 모든 것을 명확하게 설명하고 가장에게도 교훈을 구합니다.
No, it isn't. It has nothing to do with my father.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다. 아버지와는 아무 관련이 없습니다.
Because my heart delights in you, uncle. But I can't tolerate Mu Yao in my heart
내 마음이 당신을 기쁘게하기 때문입니다, 삼촌. 그러나 나는 내 마음 속에서 Mu Yao를 용납 할 수 없습니다
Cai designed for Mu Yao's frame
Mu Yao의 프레임을 위해 디자인된 Cai
- I incited them all - most
- 내가 그들을 모두 선동했습니다 - 가장
She's just a boudoir girl
그녀는 단지 내실 소녀일 뿐이야
Where could such a careful trap be laid?
이렇게 조심스러운 함정이 어디에 놓여 있을 수 있겠습니까?
you can't
넌 할 수 없어
This is the busiest street in this town.
이곳은 이 마을에서 가장 번화한 거리이다.
Look, this month is full of spring flowers.
보세요, 이 달은 화치에 봄꽃이 가득해요
and this flower
그리고 이 꽃
arrive‥
도착하다‥
watch
구경하다
There are all kinds of gadgets.
온갖 가제트가 다 있어요
Teacher, how is this house?
선생님, 이 집은 어떤가요?
It's really lively here.
여기 정말 활기가 넘치네요
she likes quiet places
그녀는 조용한 곳을 좋아한다
It's okay, I'll take you to see the next set.
괜찮아, 다음 세트 보러 데려갈게
Sir, please come inside.
선생님, 안으로 들어오세요
This house is the quietest house in the neighborhood.
이 집은 동네에서 가장 조용한 집이다.
what do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
or not
아니면
She always loved growing flowers and plants
그녀는 항상 꽃과 식물을 키우는 것을 좋아했습니다
It's so far and cold here that I don't think I'll ever survive.
이곳은 너무 멀고 추워서 절대 살아남을 수 없을 것 같아요.
-Is there nothing more? -Yes, I will take you to see the next set.
-더 이상은 없나요? -네, 다음 세트를 보러 데려가겠습니다.
or not
아니면
she likes to eat fresh fruit
그녀는 신선한 과일을 먹는 것을 좋아한다
It is best to have a backyard where you can plant fruit trees.
과일나무를 심을 수 있는 뒷마당을 갖는 것이 가장 좋습니다.
Are there any more?
더 이상 없나요?
Then I will take you to look for it.
그럼 내가 당신을 데리고 가서 찾아보도록 할게요.
What do you think of this?
이거 어떻게 생각해?
This tree is really nice, it is convenient for shade and coolness
이 나무는 정말 좋은데요, 그늘과 시원함에 편리합니다
She always likes to sit idly on the lounge chair under the eaves.
그녀는 언제나 처마 밑 라운지 의자에 멍하니 앉아 있는 걸 좋아한다.
By then
그때쯤에는
Just tie the swing under the tree.
나무 아래 그네를 묶어주면 돼요
I think it’s more comfortable than a recliner
리클라이너보다 편할 것 같아요
young master
젊은 스승
-Are you optimistic about it? -That's it.
-당신은 그것에 대해 낙관하고 있습니까? -그게 다야
great
좋아요
continued
계속되는
Thanks for watching
시청 해주셔서 감사합니다